So, in this lecture, we want to look at the 5th architectural decision or consideration
for building our January A application, which is inference optimization.
So, now, there are three ways in which you can optimize inference.
So, the first one is service tiers and capacity planning.
Now, let's take a look.
So, Amazon bedrock provides four service tiers for optimizing performance and cost.
So, the first one is reserve tier and this is best for mission critical always on workloads.
So, for this tier, reserve prioritize compute capacity for mission critical applications.
This tier targets 99.5 uptime for model response.
You need to reserve capacity for one month or three month duration.
Then it provides flexibility to allocate different input and output tokens per minute,
capacities to match requirements.
So, if you have different input and output requirements for your workload,
then there is flexibility to allocate different capacities for both input and output tokens.
And you pay a fixed price per 1K token per minute and are built monthly.
Now, how does the model actually know that this is a reserve tier request?
So, you can see here on the right, I have just pasted the Boto 3 code,
where you invoke the Amazon bedrock model with response stream.
And here, there is a configuration parameter called as service tier.
So, you can define either priority, default, flex and this is our result.
So, when your application makes a request to the Amazon bedrock and you define this configuration
parameter as service tier as reserve, then Amazon bedrock service would know that this request
is part of the reserve tier. Next, we have the priority tier, which is best for latency sensitive,
customer facing applications, but do not warrant 24 by 7 capacity reservation.
So, it delivers the fastest response time for a price premium or standard on demand pricing.
So, you can see here, standard is basically just default. So, if you don't define the service tier,
then it will go to this default mode, which is nothing but standard pricing.
So, if you define this service tier as priority, so you are charged a premium over default,
but you get priority. Then set the service tier optional parameter to priority
to avail request level prioritization. And we already discussed that.
So, you set the service tier to priority. Then next, we have the standard tier,
which is the default tier, this one and it is best for general production workloads.
So, it provides consistent performance for everyday tasks, content generation,
text analysis and so on, by default, all the inference requests are routed to the standard tier.
So, if you don't define the service tier, then it is a default or standard tier.
And then finally, we have the flex tier, which is best for cost optimized non-urgent workloads.
So, this is the lowest cost inference option. It uses spare capacity with variable latency.
So, if your workload is non-urgent and this is most common when you are using batch
inferencing, then you can define the service tier as flex. So, that way you can reduce your
inferencing cost. So, that is pretty much it from this lecture. I will see you in the next lecture.